A Guide to the Karl Maramorosch papers FA1446
Rockefeller Archive Center
Karl Maramorosch papers
1920s-1980s
Rockefeller Archive Center
Maramorosch, Karl
FA1446
7.86 Cubic Feet 6 standard record storage boxes, Boxes 1-6
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
- Karl Maramorosch Moving Images - Films, 1925-1989; 1; 8mm and Super 8mm films
  Scope and Contents
  Various home movies from around the world, including family travels, family events, and international conferences attended by Rockefeller University's Dr. Karl Maramorosch. Additionally, collection contains a 1920s family reunion in Poland.
  Titles are drawn from original film containers with some alterations based upon content viewing.
  Arrangement
  Mostly arranged alphabetically by country or subject. Films also arranged chronologically if there are multiple films from the same location.
  Conditions Governing Access
  When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  Some films are currently "Restricted." Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  Moving Images
  - Africa, 1971; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2070)
    Access copy available.
  - Arizona, 1962; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2108)
  - Around The World, 1974; Color, Silent, 24 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2161)
  - Austria, Poland, and Rumania, 1925; 1936; Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2042)
    Family Reunion in Vienna, 1925; 1936 in Austria: Jacques, Gretel, Robert - The Horvats; Kolomyja, Poland, 1936; Cernauti and Boian, Rumania, 1936.
  - Berkeley, CA and Dallas, TX, 1967-1968; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2089)
  - Boston, MA, 1963; Silent, Color, 14 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2069)
  - Cadang Cadang, Color, Silent, 25 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2177)
  - California and Hawaii, 1979; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2028)
    Locations include: Los Angeles, CA and Honolulu, HI.
  - California and Hawaii, 1985 November; Silent, Color, 7 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2116)
    Locations include: Los Angeles, California and Honolulu, Hawaii.
  - California, Pennsylvania, Bahamas, and Mauritius, 1984; 1985; Color, Silent, 21 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2175)
    Locations include: Palm Springs, California; Hershey, Pennsylvania; the Bahamas; Mauritius.
  - Canada - 1, Summer 1961; Silent, Color, 14 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2061)
    Includes: Irene Hairman
  - Canada - 2 and Vacation, 1961; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2060)
  - Canada - 3, September 1969; Silent, Color, 10 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2077)
    First International Conference on Comparative Virology, September 2-4, 1969. Persons include: Dr. Andre Lwoff (according to original container annotations).
  - Canada and Cold Spring Harbor, 1954-1959; Silent, Color, 22 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2091)
    Locations include: Niagara Falls, Cold Spring Harbor, Jones Beach, and Canada.
  - Canada, Italy, Philippines, and Niagara Falls, 1987; Color, Silent, 33 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2168)
    Locations include: Edmonton, Canada; Italy; Manila, Philippines; and Niagara Falls.
  - Caribbean, 1973; Silent, Color, 22 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2075)
  - China - 1, Color, Silent, 30 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2146)
  - China - 2, Color, Silent, 17 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2143)
  - China - 3, Color, Silent, 30 minutes; Super 8m film (Reel AV 2147)
  - Cold Spring Harbor, circa 1951-1959; Silent, Color, 15 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2112)
  - Cross Country - USA, 1969; 1971; Silent, Color, 21 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2122)
  - Cuba, 1976; Color, Silent, 25 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2162)
  - Cuba, New York World's Fair, 1984; 1939; Silent, Color, 23 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2129)
  - Denmark and Poland, 1981; Silent, Color, 24 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2029)
    Locations include the Frilandsmuseet and Tivoli Gardens in Copenhagen and multiple places in Warsaw, Poland.
  - Denver, Yellowstone, and Rocky Mountains, 1966; Silent, Color, 24 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2093)
  - East Germany and Poland, 1976; Silent, Color, 21 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2035)
    Halle, East Germany (DDR).
  - Egypt, 1974; Silent, Color, 23 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2131)
  - England and Scotland, 1964; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2073)
  - Europe - 1, 1953; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2110)
  - Europe - 2, 1953; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2107)
  - Europe - 3, 1953; Silent, Color, 11 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2106)
  - Europe - 4, 1953; Silent, Color, 11 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2105)
  - Europe - 5, 1957; Color, Silent, 25 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2180)
  - Europe - 6, 1958; Silent, Color, 22 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2098)
  - Europe - 7, Poland, 1958; Silent, Color, 24 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2099)
  - Europe - 8, 1960; Silent, Color, 15 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2097)
  - Europe - 9, Italy, 1960; Silent, Color, 25 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2063)
    Includes: Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations
  - Europe - 10, 1962 October; Silent, Color, 15 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2059)
  - Europe - 11, 1965; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2079)
  - Europe - 12, 1968; Color, Silent, 21 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2170)
  - Europe - 13, 1968; Color, Silent, 17 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2171)
  - Florida - 1, 1959; Silent, Color, 13 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2113)
  - Florida - 2, 1970; 1971; Silent, Color, 18 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2121)
  - Florida and Puerto Rico, 1973; Silent, Color, 23 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2118)
    Original can annotation: BTI (possibly Boyce Thompson Institute) Locations include: Miami, Florida
  - Florida and Canada, 1973-1974; Silent, Color, 30 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2124)
  - Florida and New York, 1980-1983; Silent, Color, 17 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2128)
    Includes: New York City (Twin Towers and United Nations building); Sixth International Conference on Invertebrate Tissue Culture in St. Augustine Florida; Castillo de San Marcos National Monument; EPCOT Center in Bay Lake, Florida; Scarsdale, New York.
  - Fulbright - 1, 1978; Silent, Color, 26 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2133)
  - Fulbright - 2, 1978; Silent, Color, 27 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2130)
  - Germany and London, 1983; Color, Silent, 33 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2148)
  - Hawaii - 1, 1973-1974; Color, Silent; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2157)
    Restricted. Please contact an RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Hawaii - 2, 1976; Color, Silent, 20 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2163)
  - Hawaii - 3, 1976; Color, Silent, 17 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2160)
  - Hawaii and Jamaica, Silent, Color, 23 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2057)
    Locations include: National Memorial Cemetery of the Pacific in Hawaii and Fort Charles in Port Royal, Jamaica.
  - Hungary and Switzerland, 1971; Silent, Color, 34 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2120)
  - India - 1 and Iran, 1960; Silent, Color, 24 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2100)
    Includes: FAO (Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations); Tehran, Iran; India.
  - India - 2, 1971 January; Silent, Color, 36 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2040)
  - India - 3, 1972 December 7; Silent, Color, 34 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2025)
  - India - 4, 1971-1972; Silent, Color, 30 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2026)
  - India - 5, 1976-1977; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2024)
  - India - 6, 1976-1977; Silent, Color, 23 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2047)
  - India - 7, 1977 December; Silent, Black and white, 25 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2043)
  - India - 8, 1979; Silent, Color, 30 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2044)
  - India - 9, 1979; Silent, Color, 27 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2037)
  - India - 10, 1980; Silent, Color, 23 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2036)
  - India - 11, 1980; Silent, Color, 13 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2027)
  - India - 12, 1982; Silent, Color, 23 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2038)
  - India - 13 and Nepal, 1985; Color, Silent, 27 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2164)
  - India - 14, 1986 January; Color, Silent, 24 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2152)
  - India - 15, Silent, Color, 24 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2068)
  - India - 16, Silent, Color, 28 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2067)
  - India - 17, Silent, Color, 26 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2066)
  - India - 18, Silent, Color, 23 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2065)
  - India - 19, Silent, Color, 21 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2064)
  - India The Ultimate Fantasy, 1987 February; December 1987; Color, Silent, 17 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2169)
  - Israel - 1, 1980; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2021)
  - Israel - 2, 1984; Color, Silent, 23 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2166)
  - Israel - 3, Color, Silent, 20 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2181)
  - Israel - 4, Color, Silent, 15 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2176)
  - Italy - 1, 1977; Silent, Color, 21 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2023)
  - Italy - 2, 1977; Silent, Color, 26 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2022)
  - Italy - 3, 1978-1979; Silent, Color, 21 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2039)
  - Japan - 1, 1965; Color, Silent, 24 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2183)
  - Japan - 2, 1980; Color, Silent, 15 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2172)
  - Japan - 3, 1980; Color, Silent, 23 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2155)
  - Japan - 4, Color, Silent, 25 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2182)
  - Japan - 5, Silent, Color, 14 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2041)
  - Japan - 6, 1984; Color, Silent, 17 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2184)
  - Japan - 7, 1986; Color, Silent, 21 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2165)
  - Japan - 8, Silent, Color, 17 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2045)
  - Kenya - 1, 1978; Color, Silent, 22 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2149)
  - Kenya - 2, 1978; 1986; Color, Silent, 20 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2142)
  - Maramorosch Family - 1, 1955; Silent, Color, 13 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2102)
  - Maramorosch Family - 2, 1959; 1961; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2083)
    Includes: Christmas 1959, Memorial Day 1961, and Christmas 1961.
  - Maramorosch Family - 3, 1963; 1966; Silent, Color, 21 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2115)
    Includes: Birthdays
  - Maramorosch Family - 4, 1975; Color, Silent, 13 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2158)
  - Maramorosch Family - 5, 1975-1976; Silent, Color, 8 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2046)
    Original title: "Lydor and Pas"
  - Mexico - 1, 1955; Silent, Color, 8 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2071)
  - Mexico - 2, 1955; Silent, Color, 14 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2050)
  - Mexico - 3, 1970-1971; Silent, Color, 20 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2101)
  - Mexico - 4, 1970-1972; Silent, Color, 29 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2119)
  - Nevada and California, 1969; Silent, Color, 24 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2084)
    Locations include: Hoover Dam, Las Vegas, Disneyland, Hearst Castle.
  - New Jersey, Puerto Rico, and Scotland, 1976; Silent, Color, 28 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2114)
    Locations include: Atlantic City, New Jersey; Puerto Rico; and the Boyd Orr building at the University of Glasgow, Scotland.
  - New York, 16, Silent, Black and white-Tint-Tone (Reel AV 2141)
  - Philippines -1, Color, Silent, 16 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2174)
  - Philippines - 2, Silent, Color, 12 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2081)
    Includes: Rice, Abaca, Fishing
  - Philippines - 3, Color, Silent, 25 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2178)
  - Philippines - 4, Silent, Color, 23 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2053)
  - Philippines and Hawaii, 1967; 1971; Silent, Color, 13 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2087)
    International Rice Research Institute (IRRI) meeting in Los Baños, Laguna, Philippines and footage of Honolulu, HI.
  - Poland - 1, 1964; Silent, Color, 24 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2076)
  - Poland - 2, 1985; Silent, Color, 10 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2109)
  - Poland, Austria, and Germany, 1976; 1977; Silent, Color, 22 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2126)
    Locations include: Poland; Vienna, Austria; and Dusseldorf, Germany.
  - Portugal and Italy, India, 1967; 1963; Silent, Color, 29 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2055)
  - Puerto Rico - 1, 1974-1975; Silent, Color, 26 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2030)
  - Puerto Rico - 2, Silent, Color, 15 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2048)
  - Puerto Rico - 3; Scarsdale, N.Y., 1983-1984 January; Silent, Color, 13 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2080)
    Film contains footage shot at University of Puerto Rico, Mayaguez.
  - Puerto Rico - 4, Silent, Color, 25 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2096)
  - Puerto Rico; Caribbean; Netherlands; Reno, Nevada; etc., 1986 April; Silent, Color, 27 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2132)
  - Raczynski, 1966-1970; Silent, Color, 22 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2123)
  - Riviera, Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2078)
  - Rockefeller Institute, 1949-1960; Silent, Color, 15 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2111)
    Subjects include: Dr. L.O. Kunkel (Plant Pathology), Dr. F.O. Holmes (Plant Pathology), Dr. Eugene L. Opie, Dr. Armin C. Braun (Plant Pathology), Dr. Peyton Rous, Dr. Max Theiler, Dr. Richard E. Shope, Dr. P.K. Olitsky, Dr. Frank L. Horsfall Jr., Dr. Rene J. Dubos, Dr. Keith R. Porter, Dr. William Trager, Dr. D.W. Woolley (Dilworth Wayne Woolley), Dr. Lyman C. Craig (Biochemistry), Dr. Alfred E. Mirsky, Dr. Walther F. Goebel, Dr. T.M. Rivers (Thomas Milton Rivers), Dr. Detlev W. Bronk, Dr. Edward Tatum, Dr. David Rockefeller, Dr. Paul Weiss, Dr. L.G. Longsworth, Esther Judkins, Dr. Henry G. Kunkel, Dr. George Palade, Dr. Fritz Lipmann, and unidentified female lab employee.
  - Rumania - 1, Silent, Color, 26 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2054)
  - Rumania - 2, Silent, Color, 21 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2072)
  - San Francisco, CA, 1965; Silent, Color, 15 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2058)
  - Scarsdale, New York, 1963-1964; Silent, Color, 21 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2090)
  - Scarsdale, Cold Spring Harbor, Washington, DC, 1957; 1958; Color, Silent, 24 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2179)
    Locations include: Scarsdale, Cold Spring Harbor, Jones Beach, Washington, DC, and Mount Vernon.
  - Scarsdale, NY and Canada, 1967-1968; Silent, Color, 19 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2104)
    Originally labeled "Scarsdale - The Wedding Anniversary. Includes footage of the moon landing TV broadcast and the 1967 International and Universal Exposition (Expo 67) in Montreal, Quebec.
  - Spain, 1975; Color, Silent, 20 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2159)
  - Sri Lanka - 1, Silent, Color, 27 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2117)
  - Sri Lanka - 2, Silent, Color, 27 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2125)
  - Sri Lanka - 3, 1982; 8mm, Silent, Color (Reel AV 2136)
  - Sri Lanka - 4, 1983; Color, Silent, 31 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2144)
  - Sri Lanka, Bangkok, Malaya, and Sarawak, 1963; Silent, Color, 24 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2052)
    Includes: FAO (Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations)
  - Thailand, 1974; Silent, Color, 29 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2032)
  - Tropics, 1976; Silent, Color, 15 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2049)
  - USSR - 1, 1966 July; Color, Silent, 26 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2173)
  - USSR - 2, 1977; Color, Silent, 31 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2153)
  - USSR - 3, 1977; Color, Silent, 26 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2154)
  - Vacation - 2, 1962; Silent, Color, 21 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2092)
    Locations include: Washington, D.C.
  - Washington, DC, etc., 1978-1980; Silent, Color, 31 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2031)
  - West Africa, 1963; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2051)
  - Yugoslavia - 1, 1972; Silent, Color, 33 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2033)
  - Yugoslavia - 2, 1972; Silent, Color, 34 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2034)
  - 1 - Rome, Orlando, Atlantic City, Israel; 2 - Bellagio and Geneva, 1 - 1985 April 12-May 8; 2 - 1985 June 2-9; Color, Silent, 27 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2145)
  - 1 - Mexico; 2 - Hong Kong, Tokyo, San Francisco, London, 1 - 1972; 2 - 1973; Color, Silent, 27 minutes; Super 8mm film (Reel AV 2156)
  - Scarsdale-Africa, Africa, 1971-1972; 1972; Silent, Color, 22 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2074)
  - Birthdays II, Silent, Color, 12 minutes; Restricted due to privacy concerns. Please refer to "FA1446_RESTRICTED_Maramorosch Films" document in the collection file. M:\Collections Management\Collections Management\Collection Files\Collection File Copies\Maramorosch, Karl papers\Restricted Material; 8mm film (Reel AV 2085)
  - Lydia: Birthdays - 1, 1950; Silent, Color, 16 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2086)
  - Lydia: Birthdays - 2, Silent, Color, 21 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2095)
  - Lydia: Birthdays; Rockefeller Institute, 1960-1961; Silent, Color, 26 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2088)
  - Lydia: 16th Birthday, 1965; Silent, Color, 10 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2094)
  - Lydia's Wedding, Silent, Color, 9 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2056)
  - Lydia and Pat Fl, Torone, Silent, Color, 9 minutes; 8mm film (Reel AV 2082)
  - 1971-2, 1971-1972; Silent, Color; 8mm film (Reel AV 2103)